Doctor Who (1963) 05x03 The Ice Warriros (Episode 3)
《神秘博士》第五季第三故事 寒冰勇士 (第三小集)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
备注: 本集字幕时间轴根据2013年发布的动画版对齐调整
VARGA: See, it is working. Zondal is coming to life. Zondal. Zondal. Zondal.
看, 起作用了。Zondal就要醒过来了, Zondal, Zondal, Zondal
JAMIE: Wish me luck, Doctor.
祝我好运, 博士
DOCTOR: You take care of yourself, Jamie, and keep an eye on Arden. I don't think he quite realises how dangerous this creature is.
你自己小心, Jamie, 盯着点Arden。我觉得他不清楚这生物有多危险
JAMIE: After what's happened here? He must be blind.
不是刚有人被袭击了吗？他要不知道就太瞎了
DOCTOR: Well, he's a scientist and a bit inclined to have his head in the air. You know what they're like.
哦, 他是个科学家, 有点一头扎在空气中。你知道他们是什么样的
JAMIE: Aye, I certainly do.
是的, 我当然知道
ARDEN: Are you all ready, lad?
你都准备好了吗, 小伙子？
JAMIE: Aye, let's away.
是, 我们走吧
DOCTOR: Good luck.
好运
ARDEN: Now we don't know how many of them there are, so we'll have to tread carefully.
既然我们也不清楚他们到底有多少, 我们必须得小心应对
CLENT: You will not expose yourself to any unnecessary violence, Arden?
不到万不得已不要采取极端手段, 你不会的吧, Arden？
ARDEN: Now listen, Clent, we both know that I'm responsible for what has happened.
现在听着, Clent, 我们都知道对于所发生的事情我是负有责任的。
If I hadn't brought that creature back here in the first place, none of this would have occurred. I also caused the death of Davis. I can't forget that, either.
如果不是我一开始把那个生物带回这里来, 这些事情都不会发生。是我造成了Davis的不幸, 我不会忘记的
CLENT: Well, you just remember your mission, that's all. And no wild sorties after the girl. It's vital that you get your information back to us immediately.
好, 你就记住你的任务就行了。不要被那个女孩儿的事情纠缠住。一有信息就马上返回才是最重要的
JAMIE: Look, we'll not leave Victoria to the warriors, if that's what you mean. If there's half a chance of us two
听着, 我们不会把 Victoria 留给那些勇士。如果你是这个意思, 我们俩半点机会也没有
CLENT: You will take your orders from Scientist Arden! Act according to your priorities, Arden.
你要听从科学家Arden的命令！ 你也得做出带队者的样子, Arden
ARDEN: Come along, boy.
来吧, 孩子
CLENT: Arden?
Arden?
ARDEN: Yes?
怎么?
CLENT: Don't be to too hard on yourself. Scientists must question, you know.
别对自己太苛刻了。科学家负责提出问题的, 你知道的。
I mean, if I'd been in your shoes I think I'd have done the same.
我的意思是, 如果当时是我, 我也会做同样的事情。
I'd have, I'd have brought it back. So, anyway, good luck.
我一样也会把它带回来。所以,不管怎样, 祝你好
DOCTOR: Good luck, Jamie!
好运, Jamie
JAMIE: And you, Doctor.
你也是, 博士
CLENT: Well, Doctor, let's see you go into action. I'll just get Miss Garrett to take you over the set-up here.
对了, 博士, 你也开始动手吧。我会让 Garrett 小姐帮你把这里准备好
DOCTOR: Miss Garrett? Oh, no, no. There's no need to go into formalities.
Garrett小姐？不用, 不用, 不用这么麻烦
CLENT: Miss Garrett? I like things done properly. Where is she?
Garrett小姐呢？我想这件事赶紧完成, 她去哪儿了
DOCTOR: Now Clent, just remember I am not a member of your staff. I'm just a working guest, as you might say.
Clent, 你得记住，我不是你团队中的一员。我只是临时来帮忙的就是了
CLENT: Yes, of course. But this is a formal establishment, and our regulations
是的, 当然。但这里的建设是正式的, 还有章程
DOCTOR: Your regulations do not apply to me. I work in my own way, freely.
你的章程对我不起作用, 我按我自己的方式来做。
CLENT: I see. Like Penley. Regulations seemed to bother him, too. Probably caused his eventual breakdown, in fact.
明白了, 就像Penly一样。这些章程似乎很困扰他, 可能正是这个导致了他最后的崩溃
DOCTOR: Breakdown? I thought you said he defected?
崩溃？我记得你说他开小差了？
CLENT: Did I? Well, one thing lead to another, naturally. He was under a great deal of pressure. Just too much for him, that's all.
是吗？哦, 事情自然是一件接着一件。他当时顶着的压力很大, 对他来说太大了, 就这样
DOCTOR: Oh, I see.
哦, 我明白了
STORR: A creature growing out of the ice! Bah!
冰里面出来一个怪物！切
PENLEY: I assure you that what I saw was very real. And terrifying.
我向你保证我所看见非常真实, 还很吓人
STORR: You've been out on the mountain too long. It takes some people that way. Especially the brainy ones.
你已经在山上呆得太久了, 就会让某些人出现这个, 尤其是用脑较多的人
PENLEY: Hmmm. Very well, don't believe me, but I still intend to find out.
唔, 好吧, 你不相信我。但我还是打算去搞明白
STORR: Ah well, you can leave me out of your fun and games. I've got enough troubles of my own.
好, 你自己去找你的乐子玩你的游戏吧, 我自己这里已经不少麻烦了
PENLEY: You're fit enough now. To do the cooking, at least. Thanks to science.
你恢复得还可以了, 至少可以做做饭。感谢科学
STORR: Science! Och, it wasn't science, it was just good plain doctoring.
科学, 哦, 可不是科学, 只是一点点简单的医术。
And if you smirk again like that, I'll crack your head open with this.
如果你还要像刚才那样傻笑, 我就那这个把你脑袋拧下来
PENLEY: Yes, you're definitely back to your normal witty self. What's the matter?
是, 但你至少又会开玩笑了是吧。什么情况？
STORR: Someone's outside.
外面有人
PENLEY: They must have tracked me here from the base. Hide yourself. We don't want you carted off to Africa yet. You!
他们肯定从基地跟着我到这里来的, 你藏起来。我们可不想你被运到非洲去
GARRETT: I followed you. It's all right, I'm alone.
我跟踪了你, 不过没关系, 就我一个人
PENLEY: What do you want?
你想要干什么
GARRETT: Elric, we're in desperate trouble at the base. You're the only one who can help us.
Elric, 我们基地陷入了大麻烦。你是唯一能帮助我们的
PENLEY: Clent doesn't need me. All he wants is a mirror. Preferably rose-tinted.
Clent 不需要我。他想要的只是一面镜子。最好还是玫瑰色的
GARRETT: He does need you, to make the ioniser work again.
他需要你, 让离子器能够恢复工作
PENLEY: Is that all?
就这个？
GARRETT: No. He's faced with having to report the full situation to World Control.
不止。他现在必须得向世界总控中心报告总体情况了
PENLEY: Oh well, now we're coming to it, aren't we? The great Clent would have to admit failure. That's it, isn't it?
哈, 那我们得去吧, 是不？伟大的Clent得承认他的失败了, 是吧
Poor old Clent. He never could face the music.
可怜的老Clent，他可能无法面对这个。
Here, what about this creature at the glacier?
对了, 那个冰川怪兽怎么样了
GARRETT: That's only part of our trouble. The real problem is the ioniser. Will you come?
那还只是麻烦的一部分。真正的问题还是离子器。你会来吗？
PENLEY: It's typical of him to send you, instead of armed guards.
还真是他的典型作风，他派你来，而不是派带武器的警卫来
GARRETT: He doesn't know I'm here. I'm asking you.
他不知道我来这里, 是我在问你
PENLEY: I won't come.
我不会去
GARRETT: But you can't just step aside. A man like you, living like a scavenger? It's utterly wrong. Civilisation needs you.
但你不能遛边站啊。一个像你这样的人, 过得像个拾荒者一样。这是全然不对的, 文明世界需要你
PENLEY: Jane, I chose this existence. I chose it because I refuse to be sucked into that computerised ant-heap you call a civilisation.
Jane, 这种情况是我自己选择的。我这么选择就是因为我拒绝那个被电脑占据的世界, 你所谓的文明世界。
I'm a man, not a machine. I will not return.
我是一个人, 不是一台机器。我不会回去的
GARRETT: Not even to save the world?
拯救世界也不管了？
PENLEY: Save the world? Well, that has a fine Clentian ring to it. No thanks, no. It'll take more than me to do that.
拯救世界？呵, 那还真是Clent的做派啊。不,谢谢了。我担当不了这个重任
But don't you worry, you don't get rid of my sort all that easily. Machines corrode and rust, but mankind goes on.
但你不要担心, 你也没法完全甩掉我这类人。机器会锈蚀会坏掉, 但人类还将继续
You'll find Clent one of these days in a museum, like that ancient stove, with an inscription round him.
到了那一天你会在博物馆里面找到Clent的, 就像那些古代的炉子, 周边还刻着铭文
Robotised human mark two, now extinct. But you'll find others like me still alive.
"机器人类第二代, 已灭绝"。不过你会发现我这类人还活着
GARRETT: Surely, Elric, that's all the more reason to come back. To change things.
当然, Elric, 这更加是你要回来的原因, 去改变一些东西
PENLEY: Don't you understand, Jane? Clent's just a talker. He's a glib political animal.
你不明白吗, Jane? Clent 只会侃侃而谈, 他是能说善道的政治动物
Even if I did change things, the Clent's of this world would still come out on top.
就算我改变了一些东西, 但这个世界的Clent还是会跑到顶上去
Running things according to their own whims and indulgences. And the pity of it is, they believe they're right.
凭着一时的喜好, 他们这样, 他们那样。但遗憾的是, 他们还认为他们是对的
GARRETT: Then you leave me no alternative. You will come, and now!
这样我就别无选择了, 你得来, 现在就走
PENLEY: You must be desperate. But tranquillising me isn't going to make it any easier. You'd never be able to carry me all that way.
你肯定都绝望了。但招安了我也不会让事情变得简单。你不可能一直这样抗着我
STORR: Oh no you don't!
哦, 你别这样
GARRETT: Who's this?
这是谁？
PENLEY: Just a friend. Now what are you going to do?
只是一个朋友。你打算干什么？
GARRETT: Return to base and wait for the inevitable disaster.
回到基地, 等着避不可避的灾难来临
STORR: Oh no, you don't. I'm not having you set the dogs on me. I'd as soon put an end to her game. Give me that.
哦, 不要这样。我可受不了这个(?), 我要终结她的这个游戏。把那个给我
PENLEY: Storr, no. She won't put us away.
Storr, 不要。她不会把我们带走的
GARRETT: No, I won't.
不, 我不会
STORR: I don't trust any of them.
他们中的任何一个我都不相信
GARRETT: Please trust me enough to come with me to safety. Apart from the danger of the glacier, these creatures.
请相信我, 跟我去是安全的地方。那些冰川才是危险的, 那些怪物
PENLEY: Oh yes, your ice warriors. Well, we shall just have to take our chance. No, I won't return. And now you must go.
哦, 对, 你的寒冰勇士。我们只能试试自己的运气了。不, 我不会回去的。你现在得走了
But if Sir Genius does have trouble with the ioniser, look up my notes on the Omega factor.
如果天才先生在离子器方面还是碰到困难的话, 翻一翻我的笔记里面关于Omega因子的那部分
GARRETT: Thank you for that at least.
谢谢你告诉我这个
STORR: This ice warrior. It's real then.
这个寒冰勇士, 是真的了？
PENLEY: Oh yes. And I'm going up there again.
是的。我打算再去那里
STORR: But why, man?
为什么？
PENLEY: Because I must know. Now, put this knife to more sensible use.
因为我必须搞明白。现在, 把这把刀用在正事上吧
VARGA: If you value life, obey, and do not anger us.
如果你惜命的话, 就照做, 不要激怒我们
VICTORIA: I want to go back to my friends.
我想回到我的朋友们那里去
VARGA: Perhaps later. For the moment, you are useful to us. Zondal.
也许晚点可以。但现在, 你对我们有用。Zondal
ZONDAL: Commander.
指挥官
VARGA: You will locate our buried spaceship without delay.
你马上定位埋在下面的飞船, 立刻进行
ZONDAL: That will not be difficult.
那应该不难
VARGA: You will excavate sufficient space to form a cave.
你倒腾一点空间出来, 形成一个洞窟
ZONDAL: A cave.
一个洞窟
VARGA: To act as a trap.
可以用作陷阱
VICTORIA: A trap? Who for?
陷阱？做什么用的？
VARGA: Do not interfere. Your friends may attack us.
不要插话。你的朋友可能攻击我们
VICTORIA: But they don't want to attack you. They could help you.
但他们不想要攻击你们, 他们可以帮你们
VARGA: We do not need help.
我们不需要帮助
VICTORIA: You'd still be frozen and dead if it wasn't for us.
如果不是我们的话, 你还在冰冻着
VARGA: You are a child.
你是个孩子
VICTORIA: Oh, why won't you listen?
哦, 你为什么不听
VARGA: Commence.
动手
VICTORIA: What are you going to do with me?
你们打算拿我怎么样？
VARGA: Bait. Bait for the trap.
诱饵, 做陷阱的诱饵
ZONDAL: Activate direction sensors. Steady.
激活方向传感器。稳定。sync
Sonic stalls ready. Set to wide impact. Take aim. Continuous fire!
split声波设备就绪。设定为大面积。瞄准, 持续喷射！
DOCTOR: If I was to reverse the sequence to give a density ratio. Where did I? Yes, here we are.
如果我反转这个过程, 加大密度。我刚才到哪儿了？对了,到这里了
If I reverse the sequence to give a density ratio. Excuse me. Excuse me! Yes.
如果我反转这个过程, 加大密度。让让，让让, 好了
CLENT: Genius at work, I see. Good morning Doctor.
工作起来就灵感爆发啊, 早上好博士
DOCTOR: Mmm? Yes.
呒, 是
CLENT: Well, this is all very impressive, Doctor, but don't you think it'd be simpler to use a computer?
这都很让人折服, 博士。但你不觉得用电脑会简单得多吗？
DOCTOR: Four. What computer?
四。什么电脑?
CLENT: The base computer.
基地的电脑
DOCTOR: Six. Yes, they're useful for digital analysis, but I very rarely use them, except when I have to.
六。是的, 用它们做做数学分析还是很有用的, 但我很少用它们, 除非万不得已。
There is one thing you could do for me which would be very important.
但有一件事你得帮我一下, 非常重要
CLENT: Yes, yes, anything. What is it?
好的, 好的, 任何事情都行。具体是。。。?
DOCTOR: Lend me a pencil. Oh, that would be even better.
借我一只铅笔。哦, 这就更好了
CLENT: Doctor, would you mind explaining just what it is that you are
博士, 你是否介意介绍一下刚才你是在。。。？
DOCTOR: Now, this is wrong, this is wrong. It's not right. There's something missing.
现在, 这样不对, 这样不对。漏了什么东西
CLENT: Would these figures help?
这些数据有帮助吗？
DOCTOR: Supposing I? What are they?
跟我说吗？这是什么？
CLENT: Data readings from the other bases.
其它基地传过来的数据
DOCTOR: Oh, computer checked, I hope?
哦, 电脑已经检查过了吧, 我想？
CLENT: Of course.
当然
DOCTOR: Oh, thank heavens for that.
哦, 感谢上天
GARRETT: Doctor, I've found something here that I think you might
博士, 我想我发现了点东西, 你可能会。。。
CLENT: Where have you been, Miss Garrett? Your instructions were to help the Doctor, were they not?
你去哪里了, Garrett 小姐？给你的指令是帮助博士, 不是吗？
GARRETT: Yes, Leader Clent. I have been looking up Scientist Penley's notes. These. Could these help?
是的, Clent 队长。我在查阅科学家Penley的笔记。这些有帮助吗？
DOCTOR: What are they? Omega. Well, what does he mean? Omega. What does he?
这是什么？Omega。他这是什么意思？Omega, 他这是。。。
Wait a minute. Wait a minute! Yes! Yes, of course.
等一下, 等一下。对了！对了, 当然是这样
The Omega Factor! There and here and there.
Omega 因子, 这里, 这里, 还有这里
Yes! Ha ha! Your friend Penley is very clever.
对了, 哈哈, 你这个朋友Penley 还真是聪明
CLENT: Is that it?
就这样？
DOCTOR: Yes, that's it!
对, 就这样
CLENT: That's fantastic.
那太棒了
DOCTOR: Oh, when you've been at it as long as I have it's nothing.
哦，如果你在这上面花我这么多时间，就不是问题了
GARRETT: Do you think it could possibly work?
你觉得这能行吗？
CLENT: It's very possible.
很有可能
DOCTOR: Possible? It's perfect! Well, it's nearly perfect.
只是可能？是完美！嗯, 基本完美
CLENT: We shall see.
我们再看看
DOCTOR: Oh, it'll work, all right.
哦, 它能行的, 没事
CLENT: The computer will confirm that, I'm sure.
电脑会证实这个的, 我肯定
DOCTOR: Computer?
电脑
GARRETT: Well, everything's checked.
是啊, 每件事都得检查一下
DOCTOR: I resent that!
我讨厌这个
CLENT: Just normal practice, Doctor.
只是惯例而已, 博士
DOCTOR: It should be the other way round.
应该反过来才对
CLENT: We have to be quite sure. It'll only take a matter of seconds.
我们必须得确保这个, 就几秒钟的事情
Copy all this down, Miss Garrett, and then we can feed it through the computer and do a simulator run. I'll just go and set it up.
把这些都抄下来, Garrett小姐。我们把它送入电脑里面去, 做一次模拟运行。我这就去把它准备好
DOCTOR: I shall demand an apology, you know.
我真需要一个道歉，是不
GARRETT: We may not have time for that.
我们可能没有这个时间
DOCTOR: Well, I'm glad you had time to look up Penley's notes.
哈, 我很高兴你有时间去看Penley 的笔记
GARRETT: I thought it might be useful.
我只是想到可能会有帮助
DOCTOR: Pity that he turned traitor.
很可惜他成了叛徒
GARRETT: Oh, Clent might call him that, but he's still the most brilliant scientist we have.
哦, Clent 才这么说他。但他仍然是我们这里最耀眼的科学家
DOCTOR: Oh? Oh, it's nice to see he still has some friends in the base.
哦, 很高兴看到他在基地里还有一些朋友
ARDEN: Glacier task unit. Leader Clent, please. Leader Clent, please.
这里是冰川任务组。呼叫组长Clent, 请回话。呼叫组长Clent, 请回话
CLENT: Clent here. Report.
我是Clent, 请讲
ARDEN: We've arrived at the glacier site. There's something strange.
我们已经到达冰川, 这里有些奇怪的情况
CLENT: What is?
是什么
ARDEN: The ice face. It's been excavated into a cave.
冰的表层, 被挖开了一个冰窟
DOCTOR: How?
怎么弄的？
ARDEN: By some kind of tool, I think.
某种工具吧, 我觉得
CLENT: Is there any sign of a spacecraft?
有没有飞船的迹象
ARDEN: Yes.
有
DOCTOR: There is? Where?
这里吗？什么地方？
ARDEN: Well, at the back of the cave, there's what looks like a metal door in the ice.
哦, 就在洞窟的后面, 冰里面看起来像是有一道金属门
ARDEN: The place is apparently deserted.
这个地方看起来已经废弃了
DOCTOR: Well make sure you don't go too near.
小心不要太靠近了
CLENT: Excuse me. Take the necessary readings, and leave quickly, Arden.
打断一下, 记录下数据就感觉离开, Arden
ARDEN: I'll take care.
我会关注的
JAMIE: What readings?
什么数据？
ARDEN: Radiation, magnetic field and ion density. Won't take long.
辐射、磁场、离子浓度, 不会花太久的
JAMIE: I don't fancy this place.
我不喜欢这个地方
ARDEN: There's never been such a discovery as this. All my life
从来没有过这样的发现, 我这一辈子
VICTORIA: No! Oh Jamie, no! What have you done to him? You killed them!
不。Jamie, 不！你把他怎么了？ 你杀了他们！
VARGA: It was necessary.
这是必要的
VICTORIA: Oh, you're monsters!
你们这些怪物
VARGA: Remove her inside.
把她弄到里面去
VICTORIA: Oh, leave me alone! Oh, please. Haven't you done enough? Please, leave me alone! I want to go back! Please!
哦, 放开我, 哦, 不要。你们还没满意吗？求你们了, 放开我！我要回去
ZONDAL: There may be more of them.
他们还有很多人
VARGA: If more of them come, we will destroy them.
如果他们再来人, 我们把他们都干掉。
If no more of them come, we will know there are not enough of them to resist us.
如果他们不再来人, 我们也就能知道他们没有多少人，不足以抵抗我们
ZONDAL: Let us destroy the girl now.
我们现在干掉这个女孩儿吧
VARGA: They came after her. She is obviously of some value to them.
他们是为她而来的, 所以看来她对他们有某种价值
ZONDAL: Then they will try again.
所以他们还是再次尝试
VARGA: We shall be ready for them. But first, Zondal, you have a task to complete.
我们要做好准备应对。但Zondal, 首先你有一个任务要完成
The propulsion unit. It must be made to function. Time is vital. You must succeed.
那个推进器, 必须要可以工作。时间很紧, 你必须成功
ZONDAL: Yes, Commander.
是, 指挥官
VARGA: Come.
来吧
CLENT: We've just finished programming the computer. We shall have the result very quickly.
我们已经完成电脑编码了, 很快就可以得到结果
DOCTOR: Isn't it about time that Arden and Jamie reported again?
是不是到了Arden 和Jamie 再次报告的时间了？
CLENT: Yes, that's true. But you know what Arden is, with his scientific curiosity.
是, 还真是。但你也知道Arden 是什么样的, 科学好奇心一上来。。。
DOCTOR: Yes, very human. I'm worried about them too.
是的, 很人性。我担心他们
CLENT: Yes, I'll do it if you don't mind. Leader Clent calling Scientist Arden. Arden? Do you receive me?
是的, 你不介意的话我来吧。组长Clent 呼叫科学家Arden。Arden, 你能收到吗？
DOCTOR: He's not answering. Perhaps something has happened to them.
他没回答, 可能发生了什么情况
CLENT: It looks as if he's. Arden. For heaven's sake man, come in!
看起来是。Arden, 老天啊, 快回答
DOCTOR: Jamie, answer me! Jamie, what's happened? Jamie! Jamie!
Jamie, 回答我！Jamie, 发生什么事了? Jamie, Jamie!
DOCTOR: I will never forgive myself if anything's happened to Jamie.
如果Jamie 出了什么事, 我不会原谅自己的
CLENT: What about this project with Arden missing?
如果Arden 失踪了, 这个项目可怎么办？
DOCTOR: Oh, your ioniser will work all right.
哦, 你的离子器会工作得很好的
CLENT: I hope so. I'm not sure that I trust your judgement yet, Doctor.
期望如此。我不确定是否能完全相信你的判断, 博士
DOCTOR: What do you mean, I'm only human? Well as a matter of fact
你什么意思？我只是人类而已？事实上。。。
GARRETT: It works!
可以了
DOCTOR: I told you it would.
我告诉过你它会的
GARRETT: The equation works!
这个方程式有效！
DOCTOR: I told you it would.
我告诉过你它会的
CLENT: Good. Good. Jolly good. Success is at last possible. Inform all ioniser bases, Miss Garrett. Thank you, Doctor. It's a triumph.
好, 好, 很好。至少有成功的可能了。通知所有离子器基地, Garrett 小姐。谢谢你, 博士, 这真是个喜讯
DOCTOR: Very likely. But somewhere, out on that ice face, are two young people for whom I have considerable affection. That is no triumph!
很可能。但我关心的两个年轻人, 还在冰面上某个地方, 这可不是喜讯
CLENT: I appreciate your feelings. I, too, have lost a colleague.
我明白你的感受。我也失去了一位同僚
DOCTOR: They're not colleagues, they're friends.
他们不是同僚, 他们是我的朋友
CLENT: We cannot be sentimental in this situation, Doctor. Our mission continues. We must all play our part.
在这种情况下我们不能感情用事, 博士。我们的任务还得继续, 我们都得做好自己的事情
DOCTOR: I've played mine. It's finished.
我已经做好了我的, 已经完成了
CLENT: What a triumph. Europe saved. Science the victor over nature, and it happened in my sector. Well, it's not the first time.
真是个喜讯啊, 欧洲得救了。科学战胜了自然, 这发生在我的辖区。哈, 这还不是第一次
GARRETT: Now we can go ahead. It only needs programming.
现在我们可以继续了, 只需要一些编程
DOCTOR: Aren't you forgetting something?
你们是不是忘记了一点事情
CLENT: I'm sorry, but some lives are bound to be lost.
抱歉, 但我们不得不付出一些牺牲
DOCTOR: No, no, I don't mean that. Arden. He's not yet completed his mission.
不, 不, 我不是指这个。Arden, 他还没有完成他的任务
GARRETT: Oh yes, of course. The spaceship reactor. We daren't proceed until we've heard from Arden.
哦, 是的, 当然。那个飞船的反应堆。我们接收到Arden 的信息之前是不能贸然继续的
CLENT: Where is he? Where is he? Where is he?
他在哪里？他在哪里？他在哪里？
STORR: What did you have to bring him back here for? Another mouth to feed.
你为什么还得把他带回来？又多了一张嘴吃饭
PENLEY: You may hate scientists, Storr, but there's no need to hate all human beings.
你可以恨科学家, Storr。但没必要恨多有的人
STORR: I don't trust anyone from Clent's base.
我信不过来自Clent 基地的任何一个
JAMIE: Who are you? Where's Arden? What happened?! Oh, my head.
你是谁？Arden 在哪儿？发生了什么？哦, 我的头
PENLEY: Now you must rest. You're suffering from severe shock. Now just lie still.
现在你必须休息, 你经受了严重的惊吓。现在好好躺着
JAMIE: Well, where am I?
那, 我在哪里？
STORR: Ah, never you mind. Somewhere safe.
啊, 别担心这个。一个安全的地方
JAMIE: Well, what happened to me and Arden?
刚才我和Arden 怎么了？
PENLEY: Arden's dead. You were both shot down by the warriors.
Arden 他死了, 你们被寒冰勇士击中了
JAMIE: Arden dead?
Arden 死了？
PENLEY: They used some sort of ray gun.
他们用了某种射线枪
JAMIE: So we failed.
这么说我们失败了
STORR: You came to rescue the girl? Is that it?
你们是来营救那个女孩儿的？是吗？
JAMIE: You've seen Victoria? Is she still alive?
你看见Victoria 了？她还或者吗？
PENLEY: Yes, she is alive.
是的, 他还活着
JAMIE: Then we can still save her! You will help me, please!
那我们还可以救她！你得帮我, 请你帮我！
PENLEY: Now you're not yet well enough. We'll discuss it later.
但你现在的情况还不够好, 我们晚点再讨论这个
JAMIE: No, it'll be to late then. They might. Oh, my head. No, you must help me save Victoria. It'll be too late.
不, 要不然就太迟了。他们可能。。。奥,我的头。你必须帮我救Victoria , 要不然来不及了
VICTORIA: Doctor, if only I could make this thing work. This is Victoria calling the Doctor or Leader Clent. This is Victoria. Please answer me.
博士, 如果我能让这个东西能用就好了。这里是Victoria, 呼叫博士或者组长Clent。我是Victoria, 请回答
ZONDAL: The girl, Commander. She will betray us.
那个女孩儿, 她会背叛我们的。指挥官
VARGA: She has courage. But she is also very stupid to think that we would not watch her every move.
她倒是有勇气。但她也很愚蠢, 以为我们不会盯着她
ZONDAL: She must be stopped.
必须得阻止她
DOCTOR: It's Victoria! Victoria, where are you?
是Victoria. 你在哪儿, Victoria?
VICTORIA: I...
我
VICTORIA: I don't know.
我不知道
VICTORIA: Some sort of cave.
某个洞穴一样的东西
DOCTOR: Are you all right?
你还好吗？
VICTORIA: Yes, but, oh Doctor, something terrible's happened!
是的, 博士。但是, 有可怕的事情要发生了
DOCTOR: What?
什么
VICTORIA: They, they've shot Jamie and Arden!
他们, 他们朝Jamie 和 Arden 开枪了
DOCTOR: What? Well, is he dead? Is, is he wounded? Is he badly wounded?
啊？那, 他死了吗？还是受伤了？伤得严重吗？
VICTORIA: I don't know.
我不知道
DOCTOR: What do you mean?
你什么意思
VICTORIA: Well, he's gone.
嗯, 他不见了
VICTORIA: Arden's body's still here and he's dead, but the warriors are from Mars, and. Oh, Doctor, it's horrible!
Arden 的尸体还在这里, 他已经死了。但那些火星上来的寒冰勇士。。。博士,太可怕了
CLENT: Keep calm, girl. We want facts. Tell us about the spacecraft first.
保持冷静, 姑娘。我们需要的是实际情况。先给我们说说飞船
VICTORIA: No, please, please listen to me. Arden's dead, and Jamie's disappeared.
不, 请, 请听我说。Arden 他死了, Jamie 也不见了
VICTORIA: Don't you understand? They're ruthless killers and they'll stop at nothing. Now please, listen to me. There's no time to lose.
你不明白吗? 他们是无情的杀手, 他们不会停止的。现在, 请听我说, 我们没时间了